Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- David Broder, undated (Box-folder 64: 27)
  Letter to Thomas Edsall. Includes a message from Frank Swoboda
- Laura Milliken, 1986 (Box-folder 64: 28)
- Book review--Rebut, Book World, 1985 April 21 (Box-folder 64: 29)
- "Why Women Suffer Most from Cuts in Welfare" (with Lexa Edsall), Sun, 1981 April 5 (Box-folder 64: 30)
- Handwritten note, 1978 November? (Box 64)
- Articles on business, Sun, undated (Box 64)
- Letters to magazines regarding articles and their addresses, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 65: 1)
- Original book outline--"A Reassessment of the Roles of the Republican and Democratic Parties,", 1982 December (Box-folder 65: 2)
- Mike Connolly, 1985 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  Correspondence (folder dated 1986)
- Review of Walter Dean Burnham, The Vanishing Voter, 1984 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  Typescript. Includes printed copy of review by Jack Beatty, New Republic, 1983 March 21
- Lester C. Thurow-—Clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 65: 5)
- Thomas Edsall's letter to Abe Rosenthal, undated, regarding New York Times reporter Ed Cowan (Box-folder 65: 6)
- Michael Weisskopf, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 7)
- Mark Reutter, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 8)
- Lewis P. Fickett, Jr., 1986 (Box-folder 65: 9)
- Julian Lapides, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 10)
- Memorabilia-—, 1985 (Box-folder 65: 11)
  Clippings, letter, and photocopy of a check
- Andy Markovitz?, undated (Box-folder 65: 12)
- Jim Rousmaniere, letter to Thomas Edsall and a printed copy of an article, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 13)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting unidentified individuals, undated
- Marcia L. Hale, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 14)
- College dialogue about Thomas Edsall's reporting?, 1964 and 1988 (Box-folder 65: 15)
- Robert Sherrill, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 16)
- Tyler Bridges, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 65: 17)
  Letter to Thomas Edsall, resume, and photocopies of articles written by him
- Ian Taylor, University of Cambridge, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 18)
- Taylor Branch, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 19)
  Letter, outline, and proposal for the creation of a research center on money in politics
- Ann C. Sheffield, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 20)
  Correspondence with Thomas Edsall regarding Frederic B. Hill. Includes related materials
- Review of Robert Kuttner's book, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 21)
- Peter Kovler, 1985 (Box-folder 65: 22)
  Clippings and photocopy of an article
- Adam Clymer, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 23)
- Good Morning America, ABC Entertainment, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 24)
- Review of Godfrey Hodgson, Lloyd's of London, New Republic, 1984 November 19 (Box-folder 65: 25)
- Murray Levin, 1986 and 1997 (Box-folder 65: 26)
  Correspondence with Thomas Edsall
- Jack Beatty, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 27)
- Thomas Edsall's articles on business, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 65: 28)
  Includes clippings, typescript, printed copies of articles, and notes
- Defense-—Articles by Gordon Thomas and others, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 65: 29)
- Advance public speaking workshop, Georgetown University continuing education program, 1983 fall (Box-folder 65: 30)
  Includes registration confirmation slips for classes and workshop in which Thomas Edsall intended to participate
- Democrats-—Thinking, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 65: 31)
  Clippings, typescript, and printed copies of articles
- Hal?, 1983 (Box-folder 65: 32)
- Standing Committee of Correspondents, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 65: 33)
- Correspondence with Fred Barnes, James I. Houck. (Box 65)
  Includes letters neither by nor to Thomas Edsall
- Publish, undated (Box-folder 66: 1)
  List of publishing contacts and notes
- "What Has Happened to the Middle Class Tax Burden?", undated (Box-folder 66: 2)
  Typescript article by Joseph J. Minarik
- Thomas Edsall's resume, 1983 (Box-folder 66: 3)
- Los Angeles Times, 1983 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  Thomas Edsall's notes
- Washington beat memorandum, 1976 (Box-folder 66: 5)
- Orenstein Dramcy?, 1990 (Box-folder 66: 6)
  Announcement only
- George A. Davidson, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 7)
- Addresses and phone numbers of colleagues, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 8)
- Stanley K. Scheinbaum, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 66: 9)
  Correspondence with Thomas Edsall, letters neither from nor to Thomas Edsall, and 1 photographic print depicting Betty and Stanley Sheinbaum and their family
- Paul Banker's? letter regarding Ernest Ferguson, 1978 spring (Box-folder 66: 10)
- Phoenix, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 11)
- Publication, undated (Box-folder 66: 12)
  Memorandum to Morales
- Thomas Edsall's letter to Jack Germond and Jules Witcover (Box-folder 66: 13)
- Tyler Bridges, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 14)
- Haynes Johnson, undated (Box-folder 66: 15)
  Notes, article, and Mary Edsall's comments
- Pat Robertson, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 16)
- Jack Beatty, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 17)
- Tom Stites, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 18)
  Clippings and correspondence
- Dotty Lynch, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 19)
- Fan mail, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 66: 20)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting Thomas O'Neil, Thomas Edsall? and other unidentified individuals, including one whose picture has been cut out, undated
- Max Stern, 1983 (Box-folder 66: 21)
  Letter with family news
- The New Republic job, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 22)
  Correspondence and a printed article
- Kevin Phillips, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 23)
- Chutkow?, 1984 (Box-folder 66: 24)
  Letter to the Edsalls
- William F. Schmick, undated (Box-folder 66: 25)
  Statement
- Shady Hill, undated (Box-folder 66: 26)
  Letters to Charles Lanning Campbell
- Vital papers-—Application for a Social Security number for Alexandra Edsall, Thomas and Mary Edsall's marriage certificate, birth certificate of Thomas Edsall, and Mary Edsall's passport (Box-folder 66: 27)
- Robert Kuttner, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 28)
  Correspondence and printed articles by Kuttner
- Post--Affirmative action, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 29)
  Letter to staff from Benjamin C. Bradlee
- Douglas Hibbs, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 66: 30)
  Correspondence and writings by Hibbs
- Harvard University, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 31)
  Airline ticket stubs for Mary Edsall
- Boston Globe, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 32)
  Letter from Mark Feeney
- Garry Wills, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 33)
- Dick Meyer, undated (Box-folder 66: 34)
  Transcripts of tapes and an article about lobbyists
- Bob Healy, undated (Box-folder 66: 35)
  Letter forwarded to Thomas Edsall
- Article, Wall Street Journal, 1986 May (Box-folder 66: 36)
- Ralph Whitehead, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 66: 37)
- List of colleges using Thomas Edsall's book, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 38)
- Review of Xandra Kayden and Eddie Mahe Jr., The Party Goes On: The Persistence of the Two-Party System in the United States, New York Review, 1986 April 24 (Box-folder 66: 39)
- Jeff Morley, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 40)
  Letter to Thomas Edsall and a response to an article
- Dissent
  - Letter to Irving Howe, 1995 October, and typescript pieces, undated (Box-folder 66: 41)
    (folder is incorrectly dated 1985)
  - Letters to Irving Howe, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 66: 42)
    Note and typescript drafts of pieces
  - Typescript drafts of pieces, 1986 January (Box-folder 66: 43)
- New York Review--The Party Goes On: The Persistence of the Two-Party System in the United States. (Box-folder 66: 44)
  Typescript drafts and final copy of the review. Includes a letter from Robert Silvers
- Irving Howe, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 66: 45)
  Letters to Irving Howe and others, clippings, notes, galley proof, and other related materials
- Herbert Gans, 1986 (Box-folder 66: 46)
  Letter
- Letters to Thomas Edsall from (Box 67)
  - Linda Davidoff, 1986 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Ernie Oakleaf, 1986
  - Joel Rogers, 1986
  - Sheldon Sturges, 1986
  - Maurice Zeitlin, 1986
  - Edward Dawson, 1987
- Letters to Thomas Edsall from (Box-folder 67: 2)
  - Paul Horowitz, undated
    (form letter)
  - Steven E. Finkel, 1993
  - Catherine E. Rudder, 1993
  - Seetha A. Srinivasan, 1993
  - Shigeo Tobita, 1993
  - Linda Chavez, 1994
  - David Gilbert, 1994
  - Amy B. Muks, 1994
  - Peter Smith, 1994
- Letters to Thomas Edsall from (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - Kenneth G. Karst, 1993
  - Raphael Sagalyn, undated
- Letter from Peter Reuter to Mary Edsall, 1992 (Box 67)
- "Strom Thurmond and the Politics of Southern Change,", 1993 (Box-folder 67: 4)
- Tyler Bridges, letters, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 67: 5)
- Day lists, 1992-1994 (Box 67)
- Lists of books to call for, 1992-1993 (Box 67)
  Includes one from Mary Edsall
- Notes, 1994 (Box 67)
  including Thomas Edsall's notes on "Masterplan Men"
- 1 photographic print depicting two unidentified young women, undated (Box 67)
- Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 67)
- Printed matter, 1993 (Box 67)
- Article by Thomas Edsall, 1993 (Box 67)
- Postcard from Juhu? and Sidney, 1991 (Box 67)
- Remarks, David N. Dinkins, Democratic Party rally, 1993 October 28 (Box 67)
- An invitation to participate in a discussion on "Religion, the American Experience, and the Press," Ethics and Public Policy Center, Washington, D.C., 1994 April 21 (Box 67)
- "Prospectus for American Men" (with Mary Edsall), 1993 (Box 67)
  Includes typescript drafts
- Article by Thomas Edsall, undated (Box 67)
- Speech, Public Affairs Network 7th annual meeting, Washington, D.C., 1994 March 20-22 (Box 67)
  Typescript notes
- Idea for Outlook, undated (Box 67)
- Daylist, 1993-1994 (Box 67)
- Lecture, Trinity College, 1994 April 11 (Box 67)
  Handwritten notes
- Article (with David S. Broder), 1994 April 23 (Box 67)
- Letters to Thomas Edsall, 1993-1994 (Box 67)
  Includes clippings
- Postcard from Michael Kazin to Mary Edsall, undated (Box 67)
- Miscellany, 1994 (Box 67)
- 3 5.25-inch computer disks--1 labeled, Chain 2, undated (Box 67)
- 8 compact sound cassettes (Box 67)
  - 1 cassette unidentified and undated (Box 67)
  - Shorr & Associates, Inc.—"Tradition" (side 1), Alan Wheat, and "Voices" (side 2), Eva Clayton (Box 67)
  - Lee Atwater I, 1985 (Box 67)
  - Ed Rollins, 1985 (Box 67)
  - Lee Atwater and Charlie Black, 1985 March (Box 67)
  - Chicalo?, 1988 (Box 67)
    (3 cassettes)
- 4 mini sound cassettes, 1986-1987 (Box 67)
- Correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 68: 1-4)
  Includes letters to Mary Edsall. Also includes clippings, birthday greetings, invitations, postcards, and reproductions of photographs
- Letter from Thomas Edsall to Arthur Gelb, undated (Box-folder 68: 5)
- Correspondence with Julius Frandsen, Max Frankel, and David Kraslow regarding job openings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  Includes an unfinished letter from Thomas Edsall to Snook? Undated
- An unsolicited and untitled manuscript by an unknown author sent to the Harper's Magazine and returned to the sender, 1972 (Box-folder 68: 7)
  Includes postal receipts and letters neither from nor to Thomas Edsall
- Movie--Clippings and newspaper, 1972; typescript fragments, notes of an anecdotal autobiography; and a printed copy of The Press by A. J. Liebling (Box-folder 68: 8)
- Article about Lawrence J. Hogan, undated (Box 68)
- "Money and Politics in Maryland"--Original chapter I, undated (Box-folder 68: 9)
  Typescript. Includes 13 unidentified photographic prints depicting a family, undated
- Article about Lawrence J. Hogan, undated (Box-folder 68: 10)
  Typescript rough drafts
- Marvin Mandel, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 69: 1-2)
  Includes clipping
- "The Daley Legacy in Baltimore,", undated (Box-folder 69: 3)
- Memorandum--Ernest B. Fergurson, 1977 (Box-folder 69: 4)
- "Changing Neighborhood"--article, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 69: 5)
- Morning Sun Critique Committee report, 1981 April 10 (Box-folder 69: 6)
- Lecture about reporting, University of Maryland, undated (Box-folder 69: 7)
- Judy Woodruff, 1978 October (Box-folder 69: 8)
  Includes an article by Ernest B. Furgurson and a letter from Paul Banker? 1978 October 5
- Ernest B. Furgurson memorandum 1977 summer, and Paul? Banker's letter, undated (Box-folder 69: 9)
- Letter of resignation from the Sun, 1981 July 10 (Box-folder 69: 10)
- "Money and Politics,", undated
  - Introduction and chapter I (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - New chapter I (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - Introduction (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - Correspondence with Pat Munroe and Peter H. Matson, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 69: 14)
- Freelance tries, 1971 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  Letters to Thomas Edsall from the New Republic and Atlantic Monthly
- Job applications and freelance tries, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 69: 16)
  Includes a typescript article about Marvin Mandel, undated
- Notes and notebooks, undated (Box 69)
- Article about Lawrence J. Hogan. (Box 69)
  Includes corrected proof
- Thomas Edsall's writings and miscellany, 1989-1997 (Box 70)
  Typescript. Includes notes by Mary Edsall, book proposals, and introduction about Thomas and Mary Edsall
- Thomas Edsall's writings and miscellany, 1989-1997 (Box 71)
- Mary Edsall's day lists, letters, and press schedule, 1994-1997 (Box 72)
- Miscellaneous materials, 1993-1997 (Box 73)
  - Letter from Mary Edsall to Jorge Dominguez, 1994 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Mary Edsall's day lists (Box 73)
  - Lists of expenses, telephone numbers, and valuation for items donated to the Salvation Army (Box 73)
  - Notes regarding new introduction for Chain Reaction (Box 73)
  - "American Discontent." (Box 73)
  - Outline for "Civilization" piece (Box 73)
  - Mary Edsall's editing of Thomas Edsall's untitled article (Box 73)
  - Notes on affirmative action and new introduction for "Chain Reaction' (Box 73)
  - Clippings and printed matter (Box 73)
  - Miscellany, 1994 (Box 73)
- Tikkun Conference, 1993, and notes to use for Tikkun roundtable telephone conversation, 1994 (Box-folder 74: 1)
- Speech guidelines, 1986 (Box-folder 74: 2)
- Fundamentals of Public Speaking, Georgetown University, 1983 October (Box-folder 74: 3)
  Course schedule
- Hard disk invoices, 1989 (Box-folder 74: 4)
- Atlantic piece on Bill Clinton, 1996 (Box-folder 74: 5)
  Typescript articles and galley proof
- File cabinets, undated (Box-folder 74: 6)
- Notes, clippings, and printed matter, 1988 (Box 74)
- Writings by Thomas Edsall-—Outline, revisions, and copy of reviews, 1995 (Box 74)
- Letters to Mary and Thomas Edsall, 1993-1994 (Box 74)
- Notes for C-Span call-in show on Power and Money, 1988 September 6 (Box 74)
- Printed matter, 1993 (Box 74)
- Day lists, 1992-1995 (Box 74)
- Miscellany, 1993-1994 (Box 74)
- Sound recordings (Box 75)
  - 94 mini sound cassettes, 1995-1997, and 1 compact sound cassette, undated
  - 95 mini sound cassettes, 1995-1997 and undated (Box 76)
- "American Men" (with Mary Edsall), 1998 (Box 77)
  - Cover page (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - Table of contents
  - Letters to Jason Epstein, Random House, 1998 January
  - List of what has been sent to Jason Epstein
  - Conversation with Kay
  - Preface (Box-folder 77: 2)
  - Chapters
    - I (Box-folder 77: 3)
    - II (Box-folder 77: 4)
    - III (Box-folder 77: 5)
    - IV (Box-folder 77: 6)
    - V (Box-folder 77: 7)
  - Miscellany, 1997-1998 (Box 77)
    Includes 2 5.25-inch computer disks
- "American Men" (with Mary Edsall), 1998 (Box 78)
  - Preface, table of contents, and chapter I (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - Chapter II (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - Chapter III (Box-folder 78: 3)
  - Chapter IV (Box-folder 78: 4)
  - Chapter V (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - Chapter VI (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Chapter VII (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - Conclusion, 1997, and info-need (Box-folder 78: 8)
- "Dan Rostenkowski," article, undated (Box 78)
- "American Men" (with Mary Edsall), 1998 (Box 79)
  - Title (Box-folder 79: 1)
  - Chapters
    - II (Box-folder 79: 2)
    - III (Box-folder 79: 3)
    - IV-VI (Box-folder 79: 4)
    - VII and conclusion (Box-folder 79: 5)
- Thomas Edsall's biographical information, undated (Box 79)
- Articles, 1998, and proof of story, "Citizenactio,", 1997 (Box 79)
- Letters and postcards, 1994-1997 (Box 79)
- Acknowledgements and related materials, 1997 (Box 79)
- Miscellany, 1992-1994 (Box 79)
- 75 3.5-inch computer disks, mostly dated 1997, containing Thomas Edsall's writings (Box 80)
- 25 mini sound cassettes of interviews, 1992-1997 (Box 81)
- 2 3.5-inch computer disks, undated (Box 81)
- Articles and printed matter, 1986-1993 (Box 81)
- New Jersey-—Clippings, 1985 (Box-folder 82: 1)
- Chicago, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, and miscellany
- California, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 82: 3)
  Includes notes, printed matter, statistical data, and charts
- Alabama
  - I, 1989 (Box-folder 82: 4)
    Includes clippings and typescript copies of articles
  - II, 1989 (Box-folder 82: 5)
    Typescript articles, clippings, electoral data, brochure, and notes
- Michael S. Kimmel, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 82: 6)
  Resume with cover letter and printed copies of articles written by him
- Randall Kennedy, 1996 (Box-folder 82: 7)
  Letter and copy of an article
- "Sexual Anarchy: The New Polygamy, The Deregulation of Sex, and Traffic in Women," book proposal by Thomas Edsall, 1992 (Box 82)
- Articles by others, 1965-1993 (Box 82)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1992-1994 (Box 82)
- Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 82)
- Writings of Thomas Edsall, 1996 (Box 83)
- Letter from Catherine E. Rudder to Thomas Edsall, 1993 (Box 82)
- Printed copy of an article by Jonathan Tilove, American Prospect, 1999 May – June (Box 82)
- Miscellany-—Name tags, press cards, and a brochure, 1990-1999 (Box 82)
- Constance Warloe, 1995 (Box-folder 84: 1)
  Includes her writings and poems, copies of photographs, guidelines for submission of writings, fragment of "I've Always Meant to Tell You: Letters to Our Mothers," An Anthology of Women Writers, and a letter to Mary Edsall, 1995
- Roger Wilkins, 1991 (Box-folder 84: 2)
  A paper and a memorandum to Thomas and Mary Edsall
- Woodstock Seminary
  - Letter from Thomas Edsall to Raymond Kemp, 1996 (Box-folder 84: 3)
  - Directory, address update, list of students, and newsletters, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 84: 4)
- Christmas poems, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 84: 5)
  Includes poems written especially for the Edsall family
- Speeches.
  Includes notes and related materials
  - 1984-1990 (Box-folder 84: 6)
  - 1991-1995 (Box-folder 84: 7)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 84: 8)
- Ronald Steel, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 84: 9)
  Articles
- Speech invitations, 1995 (Box-folder 84: 10)
  Includes letters, 1994
- New York, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 84: 11)
  Clippings and copy of a paper by Charles Brecher and Raymond D. Horton, 1990
- Ohio, 1988 (Box-folder 84: 12)
  Notes, register of electors, printed matter, copy of an article by Thomas Edsall, and miscellany
- M. K. Milliken, Jr., 1994 (Box-folder 85: 1)
- New York Review, undated (Box-folder 85: 2)
  Acknowledgement of Thomas Edsall's contribution
- W. W. Norton & Company
  - Correspondence with Thomas and Mary Edsall, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 85: 3)
    Includes comments on book proposal, clippings, and letters from Martin Kessler and Shigeo Tobita to Thomas and Mary Edsall
  - Adoption list for "New Politics,", 1965-1992 (Box-folder 85: 4)
  - Novel, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 85: 5)
    Clippings and notes. Includes one compact sound cassette on Goldwater story
- Photocopies of articles received from Carl F. Pinkele, 1996 (Box-folder 85: 6)
- Samuel L. Popkin, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  Papers and letters to Thomas and Mary Edsall and others
- Publishing, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  Includes clippings and Thomas Edsall's letter to Martin Kessler
- Publishers and agents-—Not current, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 85: 9)
  Includes clippings; correspondence with Martin Kessler and Erwin A. Glikes; letters from Raphael Sagalyn; expense record; lists of agents and publishers; and notes
- Victor G. Rodwin, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 85: 10)
  Includes brochure, printed copy of an article by Mark G. Field, catalogue, press release, and a letter to Mary Edsall
- William Schneider, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 85: 11)
  Includes "Race" (with Mary Edsall), The Atlantic Monthly; review of Chain Reaction; clippings; and copy of an article by William Schneider
- Martha Bayles and Peter Skerry, 1992 (Box-folder 85: 12)
  Articles and a letter from Robert Royal
- Tikkun conference, 1996 (Box-folder 85: 13)
  Notes, newsletter, resource catalog, clippings, printed matter, a letter to Mary Edsall from Rabbi Michael Lerner, brochures, and related materials
- George Wallace, 1968-1988 (Box-folder 85: 14)
  Clippings, printed matter, and copy of an article by Michael Dorman
- Writings by Thomas Edsall, 1996 (Box 86)
- 3.5-inch computer disks labeled "back up" (Box 86)
  - 45, undated (Box 86)
  - 1, 1995 (Box 86)
- Deutsch family (Mary's parents) (Box 87)
  - Karl Wolfgang Deutsch-—Memorial minute adopted by the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, Harvard University, and a letter from Ruth Deutsch regarding a marker for his grave, 1995; information regarding community resources for the care of the elderly; and legal agreements and financial records from Merrill Lynch (Box-folder 87: 1)
  - Peter Katzenstein, 1966-1995 (Box-folder 87: 2)
    - Correspondence with different people regarding the publication of The Integration of Switzerland: Conditions and Possibilities for the Making of a Multilingual Nation by Karl W. Deutsch and H. Weilenmann and "Backgrounds for Community: Case Studies in Large-Scale Political Unification (1963-1964)" by Karl W. Deutsch
    - Address list of various social science societies
    - Remarks by Peter Katzenstein at the memorial service for Karl Deutsch
    - Table of contents and comments on "Backgrounds for Community: Case Studies in Large-Scale Political Unification (1963-1964)" by Karl W. Deutsch and The Integration of Switzerland: Conditions and Possibilities for the Making of a Multilingual Nation by Karl W. Deutsch and H. Weilenmann
    - "Karl W. Deutsch: An Oral History"--Interview by Richard L. Merritt, Political Science Oral History Program, Pi Sigma Alpha and the American Political Science Association, 1989 September 19-21
    - Clippings and printed matter relating to the Holocaust and Madeleine Albright's Jewish origins
    - A letter from Mary Edsall regarding the affairs of her mother, Ruth Deutsch
  - Deutsch genealogy, 1987 (Box-folder 87: 3)
    Includes genealogical list; Martino Moritz; clippings about Mary Edsall's grandparents; remarks about Karl Deutsch's greatness as a social scientist-—A minute approved by the secretary of the faculty, The Center for International Affairs, Harvard University; notes; and a letter from Harley P. Holden, Harvard University Archives, acknowledging the receipt of the papers of Karl Deutsch
- W. W. Norton & Company, 1981-1997 (Box-folder 87: 4-5)
  Letters and contract relating to the GOP book
- Letters, cards, and thank you notes, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 88: 1-2)
- Articles, course outline, 1989-1990; financial records, 1989-1995; and medical records of Thomas and Mary Edsall, 1998 (Box-folder 88: 3)
- Invitation announcements, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 88: 4-5)
- Brochures, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 88: 6)
- Affirmative action and the vote-—50/50 issues, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 89: 1)
- Hayward R. Alker, Jr., 1993 (Box-folder 89: 2)
  Letters neither from nor to Thomas or Mary Edsall
- Ari Solomon, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 89: 3)
- Clippings and notes, 1992 (Box-folder 89: 4)
- Sidney Blumenthal, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 89: 5)
  Articles by and about him. Includes an article by Max Blumenthal, 1993. Clippings
- Harold J. Carroll, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 89: 6)
  Clippings and miscellany
- Harold J. Carroll and Margie Fouer, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  Clippings, printed matter, and notes
- Ned Leavitt, 1989 (Box-folder 89: 8)
- Democratic Caucus Conference agenda, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 89: 9)
  Includes conference schedule, Mary Edsall's letter to Louis R. Conte, biographical data of others, and notes
- Peter B. Edelman, 1991 (Box-folder 89: 10)
  Letter to Mary Edsall
- Thomas Edsall's biographical information, undated (Box-folder 89: 11)